

Loveland, CO 80537 | (970) 430-8559 | raseward14@gmail.com

Links

- https://www.linkedin.com/in/richard-seward-7b9336102/
- https://github.com/raseward14

• https://raseward14.github.io/Responsive-Portfolio/

Professional Summary

Motivated full stack developer with a passion for lifelong learning! Specialize in utilizing multiple programming languages & tools to create interactive online platforms that draw users in with intuitive UI's. Recently received a Certificate in Full Stack Web Development from the University of Denver. Well versed in fast paced work environments susceptible to ever changing client requests and processes.

Technical Skills

HTML5 | Node.js | Express | CSS3 | JavaScript | JQuery | React.js | React | JSX | MongoDB | MySQL | Mongoose | Handlebars | Bootstrap | Materialize | APIs | Heroku | Terminal | AJAX | Restful API | ES6 | React Hooks | JSON | Sequelize | Responsive Design | GIT | GitHub | Github | Bulma | React Strap

Relevant Experience | Projects

Loan Shark | **Full Stack Developer** | **Deployed Link:** https://loaning-sharks.herokuapp.com/ | **Github Link:** https://github.com/raseward14/loan_shark

A full stack application, built using the MERN stack to save loans, payments, and track progress towards eliminating debt! The user logs in, to view, and add their loans. Clicking loans displays payments, and allows the user to make payments, instantly updating a progress wheel showing the total percent of debt paid.

- Role: Built with React, and styled with ReactStrap on the client side, data is stored with a Mongodb database for models, Express.js and mongoose for controllers, bcrypt package hashes passwords and React tokens for user authentication.
- Utilized: React.js, React Hooks, ReactStrap, Javascript, Mongo Atlas, Heroku, Express.js, Node.js Tech Blog | Full Stack Developer | Deployed Link: https://mighty-taiga-53972.herokuapp.com/login | Github Link: https://github.com/raseward14/Tech_Blog

A CMS Style blog site where developers can publish their blog posts and comment on other developers' posts as well. Hosted by Heroku, this application follows the MVC paradigm in its architectural structure.

- **Role:** Utilized Handlebars.js for the templating language, Sequelize as the ORM, and the express-session npm package for authentication.
- **Utilized:** Handlebars.js, MySQL2, Sequelize packages to connect to MySQL database for models, Express.js API for controllers, dotenv package for environment variables, bcrypt package hashes passwords, express-session and connect-session-sequelize packages add authentication.

Work History

Coach 08/2021 to Current

ClickUp - Remote

- Leverage product knowledge to build, and design user workflows, and solve user platform problems
- Foster user success by answering platform setup questions, troubleshooting, offer advice, and suggestions via email, and virtual call

Staffing Recruiter 08/2019 to 08/2021

Elwood Staffing - Longmont, CO

• Interviewed (up to 40 daily), 200+ daily emails, recruit, onboard, offboard, orientation, counsel, resume building, job fairs

- Associate i9's ID verification, drug screens, background checks, and workers comp, HFWA 25+ client onboarding SOP's, P&L review, payroll
- Consistently exceeded year to date net income, 5-time Superior Customer Service award recipient

International English Teacher

10/2016 to 03/2019

IQ International School – Siem Reap, Siem Reap, Cambodia

- Successfully developed clear, concise lessons, classroom management, 'Back Pocket Activities', track progress, advanced MS Excel Pivot Table, Mc at school events, filmed inspiring school videos
- Developed running club, football club, cursive writing, reading comprehension, Sport & Fitness courses, library read at home program
- Built English mathematics curriculum grades 4 9

Project Management Intern

06/2016 to 09/2016

EdVenture International – Bangkok, Bangkok, Thailand

- Humanitarian educational development Southeast Asia, project logistics
- Collected "best" photos, participant reflections, leadership workshops
- Stationed in Thailand at Bantaklang elephant village, Chiang Mai, Baan Don Chai Girls School, Bangkok, and in Cambodia at Sopheak's Friendship School and Phum Oh in Siem Reap city.

Education

Full Stack Web Development Certificate

06/2021

University of Denver - Denver, CO

• Continuing education in Full Stack Development

BBA: Management & Economics

12/2014

Colorado Mesa University - Grand Junction, CO

- Graduated cum laude, 3.67 GPA, Deans List Fall 2010-Fall 2014
 - Men's Varsity XC/T&F Team: 4 yr.'s, Team Captain 2014

 - Phi Beta Lambda: 4 yr.'s Director of Membership 2012